

Alexandre MARTINEZ

Angular Tech Lead / Full-stack Developer Freelance

martinez.a.pro@gmail.com

+33 6 46 86 09 24 30 years old

Rue des Roitelets, 31700 Beauzelle, France LinkedIn: <u>/in/alexandre-martinez31000/</u> Personal website: <u>alexandremartinez.dev</u>

Online resume: French / English

I had the opportunity to work on many different projects during these last 4 years+ which allows me to give strong technical recommendations in order to produce a **performant** and **reliable product** with **unit and end-to-end testing** implementation. I stand out by my will to **adapt** to my clients needs, my dedication to produce **maintainable** solutions and my **interpersonal skills**.

Skills

Front-End

- Angular / Typescript / Javascript
- NgRx / NGXS / RxJs
- SASS / Less / Native CSS
- Karma / jasmine / Jest / ngMocks / spectator / Cypress
- Angular Material / Bootstrap 4

Tools

- MySQL / PostgreSQL / MongoDB
- Nx Workspace, Git / Gitflow / Code review
- OAuth2
- Agile methods / Scrum / SAFe
- Devops CI/CD / Gitlab / Jenkins / Bamboo

Back-End

- Server Side Rendering (Universal)
- Node.js
- graphQL, Apollo graphQL
- Java / Spring / Hibernate
- python / django
- rabbitMQ / activeMQ

Languages

- Fluent English
- Native French

Experience

Air France – Angular Developer - Freelance

Added Travel Guide on wwws.airfrance.fr and www.klm.nl, 18 millions unique users per week.

February 2022 – October 2022 (9 months) – **Angular 8/12 + Material, graphQL + Apollo, Jest + spectator**, SSR, Cypress, Nx Workspace, SAFe

- Gave technical guidance and participated in building 3 pages for Travel Guide feature:
 - wwws.airfrance.fr/travel-guide/destinations,
 - wwws.airfrance.fr/travel-guide/destinations/france/france/toulouse,
 - www.klm.nl/travel-guide/inspiration/romantic-cruise-on-the-canal-du-midi
- Data fetching through graphQL and Apollo graphQL Client
- Angular Material usage within internal UX library with emphasis on accessibility
- Test coverage with Jest + Spectator and Cypress
- Go Live in production and Live Monitoring
- Conducted heavy code reviews
- Daily english speaking during technical meetings and SCRUM ceremonies

Airbus Defense and Space – Angular Developer - Freelance

Angular library and highly customizable portal development for defense field clients.

June 2021 – Feb 2022 (9 months) – **Angular 8/12 + Material, NGRX, Karma/jasmine, ngMocks**, SAFe

- Both projects migrated from Angular 8 to 12
- Built a notification system feature
- State management with Angular and NGRX
- Advanced customization and feature toggling
- Angular Material use and applied advanced Angular Material theming
- 100% test coverage avec Karma/jasmine
- Code produced put under heavy code review
- Daily english speaking during technical/client meetings and demos

Airbus Aircraft – Lead Angular Developer - Freelance

From Microsoft to Google tools migration (e.g Outlook to Gmail) web-platform development.

February 2020 – April 2021 (15 months) – **Angular 11, python**/django, rabbitMQ, mySQL, agile

- Technical lead on the 3 front-end projects
- Two projects migrated from Angular 7 to 11 (including RxJs 5 and Http refactor)
- Built an Angular library handling authentication with OAuth2 protocol and permission management (On the front-end with Angular and on the back-end with python/Django)
- Huge work on UX and UI related topics like components style standardization
- Mentoring on Angular good practices, Artifactory, Confluence and npm scripts usage

Informatique Banque Populaire – Angular Developer - Freelance

Developed part of portal overhaul used by individuals to access their financial records.

September 2019 – December 2019 (4 months) – Angular 8 + Material, Jest, NGXS, Sass, SAFe

- Built commercial proposal feature
- State management with Angular and NGXS
- Followed internal guidelines and best practices in a strict manner
- 100% test coverage with Jest

Air France – Full-stack Developer – Angular – Java/Spring

Angular components catalog transversal to Air France IT teams development.

April 2019 – September 2019 (5 months) – **Angular 8 + Material**, **Java 8**, **activeMQ**, **Spring**, Spring Boot 2, Spring Batch, maven, **Hibernate**, postgreSQL, mongoDB, Teradata

- Multiple KPI calculations in real time or in batch processing
- Built Angular libraries consuming those in order to display valuable charts
- Data sourcing from Teradata, MongoDB or PostgreSQL
- Started working on "how to" internal AF website to guide library implementation

Internal SIRH web-platform development.

April 2018 - April 2019 (1 year) - Angular 7, angular JS, Java, Spring, Hibernate, mySQL

- Bugfixing and performance improvements on historical angularJS project
- Rebuilt historical angularJS project in modern Angular 7 application
- Handled project back-end, databases and deployment

Education

July 2018 – Level III Professional Title "Software Developer" AFPA Balma

Latest update: 21/11/2022